All right, I'll start off by just uh
want to thank our staff. I think one of
the cool parts of a draft process is
everyone's got a part. Everyone leans
into the process. Um and and and puts in
the work and on draft day you see it all
come together and um our staff is
amazing at what they do, the time that
they spend on it and the ability to work
together. Um, we found great alignment
and that created a lot of good clarity
which resulted in in a good draft and I
know we got better uh as a football
team. We added competition and usually
when you add competition uh good things
happen. So I don't know if you have
anything to say but
>> yeah, you know, I just piggyback on it.
I I couldn't be uh more pleased with
with Ryan and his crew. Uh these scouts,
they went they went out this fall and
they collected all kinds of information
and uh I mean I think they absolutely
nailed it. We found guys that fit our
DNA and what we want to be about. Um we
found it round one through round six
there, our last pick and and even in
some of these guys we're picking up
right now. U I think we're still finding
our type of guys. So that was important
for us. you would you would hope from
year one to year two with this this
coaching staff and the personnel
department we're so much further along
than we were a year ago at this time. So
that's that's what's encouraging to me
and and Ryan and uh really look forward
to to seeing these guys hit the grass
here in a couple weeks.
>> Significant roster change since January.
Where do you see improvement? Where do
you sense the football team's gotten
better since last season? Well, I I'm
going to start with uh continuity with
the coaching staff because I I really do
think um the ability for us, a a group
of guys, a lot of which we hadn't
coached together before. Um
looking to to unify that vision and
bring it to life the way that we did
last fall, we're going to be so much
better off having gone through the
cutups. Um, I know we've really refined
and made it a a big effort here this
springtime already to to get the
fundamentals, the techniques to another
level in terms of how we're teaching it
and how we're coaching it. And so, I
think it really starts there, at least
from my lens. Um, I think we'll be
better teachers of of not only the
scheme, but also, um, just the vision of
what we want our brand of football to
look like. And so, uh, in terms of the
personnel side, the the roster, um, I
think we have, just like Ryan said,
created competition really across the
board. Um, and I I really expect some of
these young players that we already had
in the program to take a huge jump from
year one to year two of this coaching
staff. Uh, and then we create a lot of
competition really at every position
group. So,
>> talk about the DNA of this class. What
is the common thread to you that you see
in these players you've got the last
three? Yeah. Well, I think Jeff King hit
it a couple days ago and that's that's
really we're looking for highlevel
competitors. Guys that if you took
football away from, they really don't
know what to do with themselves. It's
it's a huge part. They eat it, they
sleep it, they breathe it. And uh I
think we're able to identify those type
of guys. And when you have guys like
that, they usually find a way to come
out on top.
>> How similar How similar is that?
>> What strength you set
>> at safety? Um, well, that's what you
kind of from from being an offensive
guy, it's rare that you see a safety as
a guy that you really worry about. And
yet, it was pretty quickly that you
could turn on his tape and and realize
he's always around the football. He's
got a knack for the football. Um, he's a
great tackler and when he does it, he
does it with violence. And so, to me, it
his style of play showed up. I thought
Oregon did a great job putting him in a
position to succeed and uh and he really
thrived in that system and it goes back
to his Purdue days as well. I mean he
just for three straight years high level
production and then when you combine
that with the athlete that he is, the
the football IQ uh to us it was a
no-brainer um when he was there. But I
really do think he's going to be a guy
that one of those few those rare safety
types that that uh coordinators are
going to have to account for. Ben, given
how much is on a center's plate in the
NFL, but particularly in your offense,
what's the benefit here for Logan
getting to come in maybe learn for a
while under Garrett and maybe take his
time before he becomes a starter?
>> Yeah, well, I I think uh we were really
smitten with Logan throughout the
process. You know, Dan Roshark, Kyle
Dean, um they went out and and went to
several places this springtime to make
sure we we could identify the guys that
we felt really good about and and
obviously Logan was at the the top of
the list for us. And so we felt
convicted as a staff um coaching staff
and and personnel side that he was our
guy. Uh the the mental is topnotch. Um
we saw all the traits that we're looking
for uh whether it's the run game or a
pass pro and we brought him in for a top
30 and I think that's when it really
solidified it for us that yeah he he's
got the makeup. Um the guys at Iowa were
raving about him and then just the next
level in terms of uh football IQ as
well. So, I I think uh none of us have
any qualms that he'll be able to
download the information and uh once
again, it's just another spot that we'll
have high level competition at.
>> Coach, you d you draft a potential
future center. You draft a tight end who
has a specific role in your system. You
draft a kick returner and maybe a third,
fourth, fifth type of receiver, guys
type of player. Is that indicative of
you knowing exactly the types of pieces
that you can use for certain particular
roles in your offense? And then Ryan, if
I can ask this of you as well, is that a
different place to be in in terms of
roster building to be at a space where
you can use draft capital on specific
types of pieces for specific roles on
the team?
>> Well, yeah. Yeah, there's certainly
things going into the off season. Um,
you know, once again, Ryan did a great
job through free agency making sure that
we patched any major holes so that we
could go into this draft and feel like
we we could take the guys however the
board laid out. And uh you know the one
thing I I do feel pretty confident about
is this is what you know you feel good
about just tight end position for
example you got Coloulston Lovelin who
you love. You got Cole KT who you love.
Well we're really targeted at that third
tight end spot. What does it look like?
What do we value the most? Um and so
what is most appealing to us might not
be most appealing to the next guy. Same
thing with the wide receiver discussion
that you're talking about. what's most
appealing for us. And as we fill out
that room, knowing that Rome and Luther
are big components of it, we want to
find guys that help complement the skill
sets and uh and like I said, the
non-negotiable is is be the type of
players that we want to be and and so
that we can bring the vision of the the
football to life.
>> Ryan, I'm sorry. Can I get a response
from Ryan on the second part of that
question? I I think the biggest thing is
just our communication and the
communication with the front office and
and the coaching staff as we're watching
these players and and and handing that
off to our coaches. We're we're talking
about how how are we going to use this
player in our system? How how would you
use them? Where can we um emphasize
their strengths of their game? Um so we
talk about that a lot and and that goes
into the draft so we have clarity in
terms of how that player is going to
come in and and impact our team. Ben,
how is how is it for you to be in this
position as the offensive play caller
and have so much direct input into the
players being picked compared to before
uh when you were with Detroit, but now
you have such a big voice in the room
that you're getting to really handpick
guys that you need for things you want
to do.
>> Well, yeah, I think that's any head
coach in the NFL. You know, they have a
good partnership um with the with the
general manager and and what we're
looking to do is have a unified vision
on on how we want to build this football
team. And so, just like Brian alluded
to, we've got constant communication of
what we want this thing to look like.
And um I do think we're a lot further
along, you know, just in terms of our
vision and uh year two here than it was
a year ago. So, that's what that's what
fires me up the most. Ben,
>> what did you learn about in your first
year as head coach? What did you learn
that helped you focus the DNA or, you
know, at least being clear super clear
about the DNA of the kind of player you
want? Uh Ryan mentioned the other day
that it's it's just kind of a little
more focused than it had been.
>> Well, well, yeah, I think it starts with
we know what's currently in our roster
on in our locker room more than what we
did a year ago. We're still getting to
know the players. Um, and so I I think
once you've figured that piece out, you
know, you have your conversations with
coach High Tower and coach Coach Allen
and um, you know, how they see it as
well and how we want to shape it and how
we can make it better, how we can make
the whole environment um, just a little
bit little bit better. And so I think
that's really what what goes into it.
Um, we we know our our guys and so we
know what we want to mix in there a
little bit more often
>> with with today's picks. give us like a
little rundown about how it all came
together and you traded up twice and
what you like about the three defensive
guys you got today.
>> Yeah, we were just monitoring you know
the back end of this draft and you know
there was names that we were real
convicted about that again we had
clarity on what their role was going to
be um in terms of their opportunity when
they when they get here. U so we were a
little bit more aggressive with with
those names. Um, so with, you know,
Malik, um, he's he's someone that we
talked about, Al, DA, and I, um, we like
the way that he covers. We like the play
style. Um, and we think there's there's
room for him to continue to improve,
too. So, add competition to that quarter
room. Um, and we think that he can
positively impact us and give us more
depth early and as he grows into
something bigger. We'll see how that
goes. Uh, and then Keshan, you know, a
player that
physical brand of football, um, has
really good size, can run. And then
again, his ability both play to to play
the linebacker position and also help on
special teams. You know, High Tower has
a huge say in in this whole deal, too.
We want to make sure those guys can
perform on special teams, which is going
to help them make the active roster,
which is important. Um, and then
finishing up with with Jordan. Um,
again, the real cool part of this whole
process, you go through uh, you know,
your your uh, winter uh, film work and
then you get back from the combine and
then you got some guys that maybe
non-combine guys that that do really
good at proday that pop up on your
radar. Um, Jordan was one of them and as
we got his name around the building and
we were working together with the
coaches, there's a level of excitement.
Um, so he was a player that we
identified that we wanted to go get. We
didn't want to wait any longer. I don't
think he would have lasted to us in the
seventh. So, we're a little bit more
aggressive. Went and got him. Um, and
you could tell with the energy that came
through the building and especially our
Dline coaches, they were they were fired
up. So, um, really excited how we finish
this draft.
>> Savian, what about his game stimulates
your creativity offensively? What what's
a realistic way that that you can
involve him early? Well, yeah, he he's
got a unique skill set just in terms of
he's a 4-2 guy and those guys don't grow
on trees and um and so it's easy to look
at because that flashes up and everyone
sees it, but yet when you turn on the
tape, uh it's more than just being able
to run deep routes. the the versatility
that he showed uh both at Mississippi
State and at LSU from the back field um
whether it's running routes or getting
handoffs and then the the returning um
aspect of it. I I think it all adds up
and uh you know, coach Randle, myself,
Press Taylor, we all have a vision of
how this guy could could really help us.
And as I talked about, it's it's a
complement to what Rome does best,
Luther does best, Khif does best, and so
um he's a guy that we really feel like
can play a key component in what we want
to do this year.
>> Ryan and Francis St. Paul described
mannerisms you have when you're watching
T.
>> Yeah. What are they? Well, Francis said
you do some rocking and Are you aware of
the things that that you do when you
>> Well, I mean, we're sitting in the
chairs for a long time, so I just got to
shift position. But, um,
>> no, I it's it's weird. I feel like, you
know, I'll sit next to Ryan when those
scouts are in there. And, uh, I I almost
feel like we can feel each other a
little bit, which is unique for for a
couple guys that really haven't done it
together for for a very long time yet.
And so, um, there's just I think we we
he and I view players very similarly.
and and so uh I'm sure we we do kind of
feed off each other a little bit.
>> You you and Ryan both were pretty open
all offseason about needing pass rush
improvement. The fact that you didn't
sign a big name one free agency, didn't
draft an edge rusher, how is it going to
get better with the same guys who were
out there last year?
>> Well, we we're certainly going to coach
better than what we did a year ago. And
I like I said before, it starts there.
We've made a concerted effort in how
we're going to get that done. Um I'm uh
we were excited about the guys that uh
ended up finishing the season on IR. The
trajectory that they were on both Dio
and Shamar when you look at it from the
start of the season to the point where
they both got injured. We saw growth and
we saw them trend in the right direction
in terms of uh what we want to see on
game day. I think uh I think Sweat had
one of his better years in the NFL.
whether that shows up in the sack total
or not, he's he's a very complete player
uh both run game and pass game and and I
think you saw tremendous growth from
Booker when we were finally able to get
him back as well. So, um the combination
of us being able to coach better and and
those guys taking the next step as part
of this system, um you know, I I I think
we got some pretty good pieces to work
with
>> that on that front strategy at uh
quarterback as far as bringing in young
quarterbacks behind Caleb and Tyson. And
did you get some scouting intel from
Caleb on uh Miller Moss?
>> Oh, that's out already. Uh yeah, no, we
did really good work. Uh again, JT and
and some of our scouts got together and
um watched, you know, a large stack of
quarterbacks and trying to identify ones
that could come here and and compete and
perform. Um it's important to to keep
working that that quarterback room and
and making sure that we got guys that
can come here and and again add to the
competition and guys that we want to
pour into so that they can develop um
and then we'll see where it goes. Ryan,
Ryan, with the um need for a defensive
line, was it uh difficult to stay
disciplined to the board? And will you
go back and re-evaluate whether you
would have liked to be more aggressive
in parts or just what's your uh take
about the defensive line in general and
your approach to it?
>> Yeah. Uh I thought we were we were
disciplined. Again, we said this a few
times, just following the board and the
best player that was available to us.
Um, I think one thing that we take real
seriously is is each year we'll go back
and and review our process and review
the draft and and see where we could
have done something a little bit
different. Um, learn from that and then
just keep getting better as we go. But I
like the approach that we had. Um, came
away with some really good players. Um,
and like I've said before with with any
position, we're going to stay active,
see what opportunities pop up, and if we
can improve our football team, we'll do
it. Ben, throughout the process, as
you're talking about the players that
you identify having that
competitiveness, what are things you do,
whether you're talking to the player or
you're talking to Ryan, your scouts, how
do you kind of figure out guys that that
tick the way that you're looking for
this locker room?
>> Well, I always think it starts with the
tape. And so, it doesn't take long. I
think normally within the first 20
plays, you you kind of see whether those
traits show up. And if they don't, then
you keep looking. You keep looking. Um,
but eventually you kind of make a
decision whether whether you should stop
or not. And so I think our guys have
done a great job identifying who those
guys are. Um, you know, we look at the
personal character, the football
character, the makeup and all that and
and that checks the boxes. And then, you
know, fortunately, we're able to get
some guys in for top 30s, get to know
them a little bit better. The combine's
a huge part of that process as well. And
like I alluded to before, we we
sometimes we send coaches out to to meet
with guys individually as well uh at
individual pro days. So, I I think we do
a pretty good job, but it it always
starts with the tape in my opinion. I
think that's uh that's always the the
number one thing that we should be
looking for.
>> And with Rous's tape specifically, what
was that? What were those things that
popped to you?
>> Oh, yeah. I mean, he's he is a finisher
through the whistle. And uh I think that
showed up on a consistent basis. It
didn't matter who he was blocking. Could
be a big guy, could be a little DB, and
uh he consistently finished through the
whistle each and every play. Um, and you
always love it when you when you take a
player and you get a text message from
somebody. One of his coaches at Stanford
said he he will he will crush himself to
do whatever he can to help the football
team and it just verifies what you all
already thought about the thought about
the players. So, feel good about that
one.
>> Um, you said with a defensive line you
expect better results because it'll be
coached better this year. What what
needs to change with the coaching, the
approach? like what when you got met up
with the coaches this offseason. What
did you determine would go in a
different direction? How do you get
there?
>> Well, it's the the deal when you're a
first year staff, not everything's going
to look the way you want it to look. And
uh it didn't matter if it was offense or
defense. You know, fortunately, Coach
High Totower had been here, so he had
had a lot of uh time on task with a
number of guys in his unit. Uh but for
us on offense and defense, you look at
the self scout and it doesn't look the
way we want it to look. And so to me,
that's a reflection of coaching. Um and
so we're going to we we made a concerted
effort on both sides of the ball there
to make sure that we're going to get it
to look more the way that we want it to
look. And so um that's natural. I mean,
I don't think year one when I was a
first year play caller, uh did it look
the way it looked year two or year
three. So um that's natural. That's
that's how you get better. We're always
striving to improve and and uh and I
think the things that we emphasize we're
going to see improvement at.
>> Dan and Pat to close us out.
>> And back to Courtney's earlier question
on Logan, whether it's in his rookie
season or 2027, what's his path to
becoming a starter that can be reliable,
the role with all that you put on that
position?
>> Yeah, we we'll we'll see. Um we do load
guys up and and that was something that
we talked about uh when he was here on
the top 30. He knows that that that
center position is I don't want to say
it's unique to to what we ask them to
do, but um I would say we're probably on
the higher end in terms of NFL teams and
and what we ask those guys to to be able
to handle. And so um I know he's up for
the challenge. We'll we'll uh we'll see
where he's at when he gets here and how
quickly he takes to it. But um yeah, you
certainly you take a player where you
take him and and you see a you see a
future for him. There's no no question
about it. I don't know that we've
mentioned Caleb Williams name yet, but
she might be a record about Miller Mos.
>> Oh, about Miller Moss. Okay, we brought
Bill. Um, how do all these pieces fit
around Caleb, whether it's a center he
can grow with, a tight end that can help
protect him and catch passes for him?
How do those pieces fit together with a
quarterback who you know a lot more
about today than you did a year ago
today?
>> Yeah, well, I think uh just for his
sake, it's going to give us a lot of
flexibility here on offense. um you
know, we're going to have the ability to
go heavy, go 13 personnel, keep keep a
defense in in their base uh structure or
we we're going to be able to get a
little bit lighter and we got speed on
the outside. So, I think it gives us
gives him a lot of versatility to work
with and we can dictate some terms to to
the defense and and uh make sure that
we're always attacking. Um, his big goal
here is going to be to make sure he can
get up to speed with these new pass
catchers and continue to refine his
chemistry with the guys that we've
already had, which he's been he's been
working at already all uh this
offseason, last few weeks. He and I kind
of talked about I think he got all the
guys out in California and um so I know
he's been working working on that, but
um we'll hit the grass. We got one more
week of phase one. we'll hit the hit the
grass for phase two and and we'll really
be able to hone in on some of those
details of of where he can get better
with his teammates.
>> Awesome. Thank you.